<metadata><eainfo><overview><eaover>Attributes definitions and data schema can be found within the Trails and Bikeways Data Specification document. 

Schema Version 1.2
https://www.metrogis.org/projects/park-and-trail.aspx</eaover></overview></eainfo><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Metro Park and Trail Data Collaborative</origin><title>Metro Collaborative Trails and Bikeways</title><pubinfo><publish>MetroGIS</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>20200203</pubdate><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/us-mn-state-metrogis-trans-metro-colabtiv-trails-bike</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This dataset was created by the Metro Trails and Bikeways Collaborative, a joint collaborative project involving the technical and managerial GIS staff from the Seven Metropolitan Counties (Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington). Data were gathered from local, state, and federal partners by the project team and put into the metro data model.</abstract><purpose>The goal of the Metro Trails and Bikeways project is to facilitate the creation and sustained maintenance of a metro-wide dataset that can be used to meet the needs of local and regional agencies, as well as residents.</purpose></descript><crossref><citeinfo><title>Metro Collaborative Parks</title></citeinfo></crossref><timeperd><current>This dataset is aggregated by MetroGIS and published as a regional dataset. The data is current as of the listed Publication Date. It will be aggregated in July and January, or more frequently depending on need and availability of updates from the participating agencies.</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20200203</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>In work</progress><update>Twice Annual</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.012</westbc><eastbc>-92.732</eastbc><northbc>45.415</northbc><southbc>44.471</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekey>trails, bikeways, transportation, bike, biking, bicycling, bicycle, recreation, parks, routes, active living, healthy, open, free</themekey></theme><place><placekey>metro, anoka, carver, dakota, hennepin, ramsey, scott, washington</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). If the dataset is not available from the Online Linkage in Section 6, please contact the Distribution Contact Person.</accconst><useconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Ramsey County</cntorg><cntper>Geoff Maas</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Geospatial Business Analyst</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>121 7th Place East</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>763.772.4287</cntvoice><cntemail>geoffrey.maas@co.ramsey.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><complete>The data is offered ‘as is’ and is sourced from the best available municipal, county, state and federal datasets drawn together into the Metro Park and Trail data standard. Not all attributes may be populated at this time, however, future iterations of the data set endeavor to continue to add attribute date.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>This varies between counties</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>NA</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>This dataset was assembled from data created by the GIS offices of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington Counties, participating in the Metro Park and Trail Build Team under the direction of the county GIS managers. Agencies participating in the Metro Park and Trail Data Project have provided data as fully as possible from known sources to meet the documented business needs expressed by the agencies. 

https://www.metrogis.org/projects/park-and-trail.aspx</procdesc></procstep></lineage></dataqual><distinfo><resdesc>MetroCollaborativeTrailsBikeways</resdesc><distliab>NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><stdorder><ordering>See Online Linkage Below</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Ramsey County</cntorg><cntper>Geoff Maas</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Geospatial Business Analyst</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>121 7th Place East</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>763.772.4287</cntvoice><cntemail>geoffrey.maas@co.ramsey.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20200203</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Ramsey County</cntorg><cntper>Geoff Maas</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Geospatial Business Analyst</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>121 7th Place East</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>763.772.4287</cntvoice><cntemail>geoffrey.maas@co.ramsey.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>